
/* JavaQuiz Questions
 * creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
 */

let questions = [
/* Q1 */     
  {
      numb: 1,
      question: "Java is a ___________ programming language",
      options: [
                "A) sequence-dependent",
                "B) code-dependent",
                "C) platform-dependent",
                "D) platform-independent"
               ],
      answer: "D) platform-independent"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q2 */     
  {
      numb: 2,
      question: "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
      options: [
                "A) JRE",
                "B) JIT",
                "C) JDK",
                "D) JVM"
               ],
      answer: "C) JDK"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q3 */     
  {
      numb: 3,
      question: "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
      options: [
                "A) Object-oriented",
                "B) Use of pointers",
                "C) Portable",
                "D) Dynamic and Extensible"
               ],
      answer: "B) Use of pointers"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
  
/* Q4 */     
  {
      numb: 4,
      question: "Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
      options: [
                "A) identifier & keyword",
                "B) identifier",
                "C) keyword",
                "D) none of the mentioned"
               ],
      answer: "C) keyword"
    },
/*Copy till here*/
  
/* Q5 */     
  {
      numb: 5,
      question: "What is the extension of java code files?",
      options: [
                "A) .js",
                "B) .txt",
                "C) .class",
                "D) .java"
               ],
      answer: "D) .java"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q6 */     
  {
      numb: 6,
      question: "Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
      options: [
                "A) MAVEN_Path",
                "B) JavaPATH",
                "C) JAVA",
                "D) JAVA_HOME"
               ],
      answer: "D) JAVA_HOME"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q7 */     
  {
      numb: 7,
      question: "Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
      options: [
                "A) Polymorphism",
                "B) Inheritance",
                "C) Compilation",
                "D) Encapsulation"
               ],
      answer: "C) Compilation"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q8 */ 
  {
      numb: 8,
      question: "Which of these keywords is used to define interfaces in Java?",
      options: [
                "A) intf",
                "B) Intf",
                "C) interface",
                "D) Interface"
               ],
      answer: "C) interface"
    },
/*Copy till here*/

/* Q9 */ 
  {
      numb: 9,
      question: "What is not the use of <span style='color: violet'>this</span> keyword in Java?",
      options: [
                "A) Referring to the instance variable when a local variable has the same name",
                "B) Passing itself to the method of the same class",
                "C) Passing itself to another method",
                "D) Calling another constructor in constructor chaining"
               ],
      answer: "B) Passing itself to the method of the same class"
    },
/*Copy till here*/


/* Q10 */    
  {
      numb: 10,
      question: "Which exception is thrown when java is out of memory?",
      options: [
                "A) MemoryError",
                "B) OutOfMemoryError",
                "C) MemoryOutOfBoundsException",
                "D) MemoryFullException"
               ],
      answer: "B) OutOfMemoryError"
    },
/*Copy till here*/




]; /* Array close*/